<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Jason Meridth's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/</link><description>Learn, Converse, Share</description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 23:42:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Not a fan of Ubuntu Unity, trying out Cinnamon desktop environment</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/not-a-fan-of-ubuntu-unity-trying-out-cinnamon-desktop-environment/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; switched to Linux as my native OS (Ubuntu 14.04 LTS specifically) I have been having a blast.  My only complaint has been Unity.  It is not user friendly.  It makes my 8GB RAM laptop go slow.  I even researched disabling it.  Seems that is quite the feat in Ubuntu these days.  I'm a minimalist when it comes to my computers.  I remember Gnome and have always been a fan.  However, due to an article I read the other day, I decided to read up on &lt;a href="http://linuxmint.com"&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/a&gt; and remembered a co-worker was using it as his primary OS.  I have also been playing with Fedora more lately due to its support for containers.  I feel that is the future on application deployments.  However, since Mint is based on Debian and Ubuntu, it is more of a comfort thing for me.  My co-workers suggestion was to try out &lt;a href="http://cinnamon.linuxmint.com0"&gt;Cinnamon&lt;/a&gt;.  As an Ubuntu package for cinnamon is &lt;a href="http://askubuntu.com/questions/94201/how-do-i-install-the-cinnamon-desktop"&gt;no longer maintained&lt;/a&gt;, I found a PPA that is still being maintained of the Cinnamon &lt;em&gt;stable&lt;/em&gt; branch (yes, I am aware the Cinnamon maintainer has a PPA for nightly builds, but I'm not quite that brave).  I installed it with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;sudo add-apt-repository ppa:lestcape/cinnamon
sudo apt-get install cinnamon
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Once installed you need to logout and choose Cinnamon from the login session screen, like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cinnamon" src="http://b038a8f209e36fc36fba-a9b634eed6b534d774260bd8467c190d.r61.cf1.rackcdn.com/Cinnamon-login.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that you will see a much more responsive UI.  And for you Windows users, it will feel very familiar, as the taskbar and icons are in the usual locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: To those that actually read this, I did try &lt;a href="http://packages.ubuntu.com/trusty/gnome-session-fallback"&gt;gnome session fallback&lt;/a&gt; and had many issues with it.  I am also aware that there is an official &lt;a href="http://ubuntugnome.org/"&gt;Ubuntu Gnome&lt;/a&gt; variant of Ubuntu now also.  Hadn't tried it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/not-a-fan-of-ubuntu-unity-trying-out-cinnamon-desktop-environment/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 04:11:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Copying Text With Mouse In TMUX</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/copying-text-with-mouse-in-tmux/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;TL;DR
Hold down shift key and select text with left mouse button.  This will copy to clipboard.  Then hold down the shift key again and click the middle button on your mouse.  Voila!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long version:
After finally moving over to Ubuntu as my native operating system, I've been using the default Terminal application for development.  I run my weechat IRC session on a remote node in TMUX so I can detach/reattach at will and stay connected.  I'm using ZNC as my bounce also in case the tmux session or weechat crashes.  This means it stays connected and will replay anything I missed while disconnected.  Anyway, I have had issues with copy/paste in the Terminal app, especially when my development sessions are in TMUX.  I've been using Ctrl+Shift and selecting text and it has been working, but has been adding a newline on the end when I use Ctrl+Shift+V (paste).  Hodling down the shift key was the trick.  Hold down the shift key and select text with left mouse button.  This will copy to clipboard.  Then hold down the shift key again and click the middle button on your mouse.  This will paste the text WITHOUT a newline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://awhan.wordpress.com/2012/04/18/tmux-copy-paste-with-mouse/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>tmux</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/copying-text-with-mouse-in-tmux/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 14:46:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting a Canon MX450 Series Working With Ubuntu 14.04</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/getting-a-canon-mx450-series-working-with-ubuntu-1404/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I needed to scan something on my Canon MX450 series printer from my laptop running Ubuntu 14.04 LTS.  I had already setup the printer portion successfully with the built in network printer detection, but hadn't done the scanning portion.  I found out I needed to download a deb file and install something called scangearmp to get this to work.  The download button can be found &lt;a href="http://support-sg.canon-asia.com/contents/SG/EN/0100517701.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  As of this post I've download version 2.10 which was last updated on 14-Feb-2013, Issue Number 0100517701.  Once downloaded issue the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;tar xzf scangearmp-mx450series-2.10-1-deb.tar.gz
cd scangearmp-mx450series-2.10-1-deb/
sudo ./install.sh
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This will install the scangearmp binary to /usr/bin/scangearmp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now all you need to do is run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;scangearmp
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you you don't see a scanner listed in the dropdown then you just need to push the "Update Scanner List" button and it should find your scanner.  After that you should see the same popup but now with your Canon MX450 scanner listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="SelectScanner" src="http://b038a8f209e36fc36fba-a9b634eed6b534d774260bd8467c190d.r61.cf1.rackcdn.com/selectscanner.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps someone else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><category>troubleshooting</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/getting-a-canon-mx450-series-working-with-ubuntu-1404/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 03:03:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Restarting Audio in Ubuntu After Issues</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/restarting-audio-in-ubuntu-after-issues/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following command restarted audio for me in Ubuntu after my microphone on my headphones stopped working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;pulseaudio -k &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo alsa force-reload
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Credit to: &lt;a href="http://askubuntu.com/a/230893"&gt;http://askubuntu.com/a/230893&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/restarting-audio-in-ubuntu-after-issues/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 17:12:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I Finally Have Linux As My Native OS</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/i-finally-have-linux-as-my-native-os/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I finally replaced OSX on my Mac with Ubuntu 14.04 LTS.  Out of the box I've had no issues.  Wireless, VPN, Terminal, Dropbox, Google Drive, LastPass, etc all work.  I was spending more time in my &lt;a href="https://www.vagrantup.com/"&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; VMs with OSX anyway.  Loved &lt;a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/"&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; + Vagrant.  Never had an issue.  I just wasn't using any portion of OSX.  It is nice to troubleshoot any issues and tweak my setup.  I'm getting used to Unity and may drop it for Gnome3 and Gnome-Do.  We'll see.  Any new things I troubleshoot or find, I'll post on.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>linux</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/i-finally-have-linux-as-my-native-os/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 23:27:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Learning Android Development</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/learning-android-development/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I've decided to take the new &lt;a href="http://coursera.org"&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://class.coursera.org/androidpart1-001"&gt;Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems: Part 1&lt;/a&gt; to see if it can give me more insight past the "Intro to Android" tutorials I've already done before.  There are subsequent classes after this one, so we'll see how it goes.  I plan to blog after each assignment to get my thoughts out and anything interesting I've learned.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>android</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/learning-android-development/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 23:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why I Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/why-i-blog/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been asked recently why I blog.  My answer is the same since I started blogging back in 2006.  I blog for three reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I figured out a problem/issue I was having and want to share the knowledge.  If I had the problem/issue, someone else will and hopefully google will link to my post and help them when they are searching. What I've also experienced is someone reads my post and comments with a better and/or more efficient solution.  I then can link to their comment/post or update my own.  I love that sense of community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will use a different part of my brain to write the post and, therefore (hopefully), remember the solution better next time this particular problem/issue arises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to store the solution online, not only on my local computer (aka isolation), so that I, and others, can reference it in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; blog because I think it will make me popular or because I want to seem smarter than anyone else.  I enjoy learning and sharing information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>information</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/why-i-blog/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 14:43:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>When Git or SSH Protocols Blocked</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/when-git-or-ssh-protocols-blocked/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently I had issues connecting to &lt;a href="http://github.com/roaet"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; because of some firewall restrictions outside my control.  The firewall had outbound SSH (port 22) blocked.  My co-worker &lt;a href="https://github.com"&gt;Justin Hammond&lt;/a&gt; found a git config option that lets you force all git commands to use &lt;code&gt;https://&lt;/code&gt; (port 443) instead of &lt;code&gt;git://&lt;/code&gt; (port 22).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;git config --global url.&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"https://"&lt;/span&gt;.insteadOf git://
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Worked like a charm.  Thanks Justin.  Hope this helps someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NB: Don't use &lt;code&gt;--global&lt;/code&gt; if you don't want this applied to all repositories.  Without it only sets for the current repository you're in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>git</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/when-git-or-ssh-protocols-blocked/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 13:47:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weechat keyboard shortcuts</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/weechat-keyboard-shortcuts/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've switched from using irssi to &lt;a href="http://weechat.org"&gt;Weechat&lt;/a&gt; since I rejoined the ranks as a &lt;a href="http://www.rackspace.com"&gt;Racker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/jmeridth/dotfiles/blob/master/weechat.conf"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is my current weechat.conf file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the ones I use often:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+h - window left&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+j - window down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+k - window up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+l - window right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+z - window zoom (make current small window full screen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+n - next buffer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+p - previous buffer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+y - clipboard paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+r - search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+[j|m] - stop search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;normal commands not included with my weechat.conf that I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/window resize &lt;number&gt; - resizes window to that percentage&lt;/number&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/buffer clear - clears the buffer, i use this often with the &lt;a href="http://weechat.org/scripts/source/highmon.pl.html/"&gt;highlight monitor plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/buffer merge &lt;other buffer number&gt; - merges two buffers into one (use ctrl+x to switch between them)&lt;/other&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/buffer unmerge - unmerge the buffer you're currently on out to its own&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cli</category><category>irc</category><category>weechat</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/weechat-keyboard-shortcuts/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 04:52:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Where I Go To Choose An Open Source License</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/where-i-go-to-choose-an-open-source-license/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I go to &lt;a href="http://choosealicense.com"&gt;choosealicense.com&lt;/a&gt; to refresh my memory on open source licenses.  &lt;a href="http://choosealicense.com/licenses/mit/"&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; is usually my favorite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good resource, in my opinion&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>open source</category><category>resources</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/where-i-go-to-choose-an-open-source-license/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 04:50:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>