<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Github on Learn, Converse, Share</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in Github on Learn, Converse, Share</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:55:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jmeridth.com/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New Job: GitHub</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/new-job-github/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:55:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/new-job-github/</guid><description>I have landed a new gig at GitHub. I will be a Senior Software Engineer on the GitHub OSPO (Open Source Program Office) team. I am super excited to be working with this team and this company.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Contribute URL</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/github-contribute-url/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:33:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/github-contribute-url/</guid><description>I sometimes get asked what is the best way to contribute to an open-source project. If the project is hosted on GitHub, there is a helper URL for each repository that will highlight any issues that the maintainers have labelled with good first issue or help wanted.
that URL is /contribute on the the end of the repository URL. For example, the URL for the github.com/jmeridth/jmeridth.github.io repository is https://github.com/jmeridth/jmeridth.github.io/contribute
You can search multiple repositories with GitHub&amp;rsquo;s new https://forgoodfirstissue.</description></item><item><title>Details HTML Section In Github Issues and Gists</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/details-html-section-in-github-issues-and-gists/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 11:01:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/details-html-section-in-github-issues-and-gists/</guid><description>I recently became aware of using the &amp;lt;details&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/details&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;summary&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/summary&amp;gt; tags in Github issues and Gists.
Here is an example.
I will definitely be using this more when posting big logs or stack traces.
Kudos:
Laura Frank for showing me this feature Keith Dahlby for letting me know it doesn&amp;rsquo;t currently work in Firefox Matt Hinze for showing me this gist where I learned of &amp;lt;summary&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/summary&amp;gt; Eric Clemmons for the awesome gist that does a great job explaining the feature</description></item><item><title>Do Not Issue Pull Requests From Your Master Branch</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/do-not-issue-pull-requests-from-your-master-branch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/do-not-issue-pull-requests-from-your-master-branch/</guid><description>PROBLEM: You do not want to issue pull requests from your fork’s master branch on Github.com to the parent repository because any new changes you add to the master branch will automatically show up in the pull request. That means changes you did not intend to be there, would now be there.
SOLUTION: Issue your pull requests from a feature/topic branch
BAD SCENARIO:
Fork repo ABC Clone it locally (git clone git@github.</description></item></channel></rss>