<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Firefox on Learn, Converse, Share</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/tags/firefox/</link><description>Recent content in Firefox on Learn, Converse, Share</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 03:26:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jmeridth.com/tags/firefox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MSDN - can't download with firefox</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/msdn-can-t-download-with-firefox/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 03:26:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/msdn-can-t-download-with-firefox/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m on Linux.  Getting this to work on Windows is simple enough, just like James mentions in the comments. Thanks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this, because it&amp;rsquo;s about the 5th time I&amp;rsquo;ve had to use my Windows box or VM to get iso files from MSDN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;rant&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand, in a business manner, why Microsoft won&amp;rsquo;t allow downloads from Firefox at MSDN.  I work for a company that was kind enough to give me a MSDN license.  I&amp;rsquo;ve used it a great deal to get software like Vistual Studio 2008 and SQL Server 2008 recently.  I also use it for the iso files I use in my VMs.  I recently had to download Vista again and from Firefox the specific items I want (the checkboxes in MSDN&amp;rsquo;s new Silverlight UI) are grayed out.  COME ON!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ubutnu 8.04 (Hardy Heron) after upgrade - I have complete sound!!</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/ubutnu-8-04-hardy-heron-after-upgrade-i-have-complete-sound/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 16:46:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/ubutnu-8-04-hardy-heron-after-upgrade-i-have-complete-sound/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: Do not upgrade your virtual box install.  Stay with the Gutsy version if you already have it.  If you are just installing Hardy Heron from scratch, I will have a post in a little bit and link to it here about how to ensure you get the correct version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous &lt;a href="http://jmeridth.com/blogs/jason_meridth/archive/2007/05/12/getting-sound-working-on-my-toshiba-laptop-with-ubuntu-7-04-feisty-fawn.aspx" &gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, I shared the pain of getting sound working on my Toshiba Satellite laptop with prior versions of Ubuntu.  It has been off and on for a while and I&amp;rsquo;ve even resorting to recompiling my kernel to get it to work (no luck).  After upgrading to Hardy Heron today and restarting, I heard the wonderful drum sounds you here when Ubuntu loands.  YIPEE!!  I just logged in and finally got to watch some of the CodeBetter screencasts on the Seattle conference on my laptop without having to use my Windows VM.  For some reason, when I plugged headphones in and used my Windows VM, I got sound.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>