<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Learn, Converse, Share</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Learn, Converse, Share</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 16:19:57 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jmeridth.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Studying for RHCSA/RHCE Exams</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/studying-for-rhcsarhce-exams/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 16:19:57 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/studying-for-rhcsarhce-exams/</guid><description>Update: I had to put this on hold due to a job switch and haven&amp;rsquo;t studied any further or signed up for an exam again - 1/6/2015
I have decided to finally get the RHCSA and RHCE certifications. RHCSA stands for Redhat Certified System Adminitrator and RHCE stands for Redhat Certified Engineer. The reason I decided on these exams is for 2 reasons:
They are not multiple choice. You sit at a kiosk with VNC and are given a live RHEL (Redhat Enterprise Linux) instance and are given issues to fix (aka Real World) A stepping stone to me finally taking my Linux knowledge/skills seriously.</description></item><item><title>Not a fan of Ubuntu Unity, trying out Cinnamon desktop environment</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/not-a-fan-of-ubuntu-unity-trying-out-cinnamon-desktop-environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 22:11:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/not-a-fan-of-ubuntu-unity-trying-out-cinnamon-desktop-environment/</guid><description>Since I finally switched to Linux as my native OS (Ubuntu 14.04 LTS specifically) I have been having a blast. My only complaint has been Unity. It is not user friendly. It makes my 8GB RAM laptop go slow. I even researched disabling it. Seems that is quite the feat in Ubuntu these days. I&amp;rsquo;m a minimalist when it comes to my computers. I remember Gnome and have always been a fan.</description></item><item><title>Getting a Canon MX450 Series Working With Ubuntu 14.04</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/getting-a-canon-mx450-series-working-with-ubuntu-1404/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 21:03:55 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/getting-a-canon-mx450-series-working-with-ubuntu-1404/</guid><description>Today I needed to scan something on my Canon MX450 series printer from my laptop running Ubuntu 14.04 LTS. I had already setup the printer portion successfully with the built in network printer detection, but hadn&amp;rsquo;t done the scanning portion. I found out I needed to download a deb file and install something called scangearmp to get this to work. The download button can be found here. As of this post I&amp;rsquo;ve download version 2.</description></item><item><title>Restarting Audio in Ubuntu After Issues</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/restarting-audio-in-ubuntu-after-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 11:12:14 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/restarting-audio-in-ubuntu-after-issues/</guid><description>The following command restarted audio for me in Ubuntu after my microphone on my headphones stopped working.
pulseaudio -k &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo alsa force-reload Credit to: http://askubuntu.com/a/230893</description></item><item><title>I Finally Have Linux As My Native OS</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/i-finally-have-linux-as-my-native-os/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 17:27:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/i-finally-have-linux-as-my-native-os/</guid><description>I finally replaced OSX on my Mac with Ubuntu 14.04 LTS. Out of the box I&amp;rsquo;ve had no issues. Wireless, VPN, Terminal, Dropbox, Google Drive, LastPass, etc all work. I was spending more time in my Vagrant VMs with OSX anyway. Loved VirtualBox + Vagrant. Never had an issue. I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t using any portion of OSX. It is nice to troubleshoot any issues and tweak my setup. I&amp;rsquo;m getting used to Unity and may drop it for Gnome3 and Gnome-Do.</description></item></channel></rss>