<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Jason Meridth's Blog (information)</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/categories/information.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 17:31:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Why I Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/why-i-blog/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been asked recently why I blog.  My answer is the same since I started blogging back in 2006.  I blog for three reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I figured out a problem/issue I was having and want to share the knowledge.  If I had the problem/issue, someone else will and hopefully google will link to my post and help them when they are searching. What I've also experienced is someone reads my post and comments with a better and/or more efficient solution.  I then can link to their comment/post or update my own.  I love that sense of community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will use a different part of my brain to write the post and, therefore (hopefully), remember the solution better next time this particular problem/issue arises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to store the solution online, not only on my local computer (aka isolation), so that I, and others, can reference it in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; blog because I think it will make me popular or because I want to seem smarter than anyone else.  I enjoy learning and sharing information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>information</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/why-i-blog/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 14:43:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Slicehost Articles</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/slicehost-articles/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are Linux newbie or are still unsure about how to setup your &lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt; box/slice/server, take a serious look at the &lt;a href="http://articles.slicehost.com/"&gt;Slicehost Articles&lt;/a&gt;.  Other articles include setup of Apache, Nginx, Postfix, MySQL, Ruby on Rails, Capistrano, SSH, Self-signed certificates, Django, etc.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the Only Windows guys who read this, these articles are a great way to get your feet wet with Linux.  Can't hurt your pocket book.  It's free. &lt;a href="http://www.ubuntu.com"&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; is currently my favorite distribution.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/armmer"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; about this a number of times.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These articles are phenomenal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>help</category><category>information</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/slicehost-articles/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 10:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>