<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Jason Meridth's Blog (linux)</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/categories/linux.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 16:27:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Studying for RHCSA/RHCE Exams</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/studying-for-rhcsarhce-exams/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have decided to finally get the RHCSA and RHCE certifications.  RHCSA stands for Redhat Certified System Adminitrator and RHCE stands for Redhat Certified Engineer.  The reason I decided on these exams is for 2 reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are not multiple choice.  You sit at a kiosk with VNC and are given a live RHEL (Redhat Enterprise Linux) instance and are given issues to fix (aka Real World)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A stepping stone to me finally taking my Linux knowledge/skills seriously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note, I've been using linux for 17 years.  I've managed multiple systems to hundreds of VMs.  I'll keep you posted on how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>certifications</category><category>linux</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/studying-for-rhcsarhce-exams/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 22:19:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Not a fan of Ubuntu Unity, trying out Cinnamon desktop environment</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/not-a-fan-of-ubuntu-unity-trying-out-cinnamon-desktop-environment/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; switched to Linux as my native OS (Ubuntu 14.04 LTS specifically) I have been having a blast.  My only complaint has been Unity.  It is not user friendly.  It makes my 8GB RAM laptop go slow.  I even researched disabling it.  Seems that is quite the feat in Ubuntu these days.  I'm a minimalist when it comes to my computers.  I remember Gnome and have always been a fan.  However, due to an article I read the other day, I decided to read up on &lt;a href="http://linuxmint.com"&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/a&gt; and remembered a co-worker was using it as his primary OS.  I have also been playing with Fedora more lately due to its support for containers.  I feel that is the future on application deployments.  However, since Mint is based on Debian and Ubuntu, it is more of a comfort thing for me.  My co-workers suggestion was to try out &lt;a href="http://cinnamon.linuxmint.com0"&gt;Cinnamon&lt;/a&gt;.  As an Ubuntu package for cinnamon is &lt;a href="http://askubuntu.com/questions/94201/how-do-i-install-the-cinnamon-desktop"&gt;no longer maintained&lt;/a&gt;, I found a PPA that is still being maintained of the Cinnamon &lt;em&gt;stable&lt;/em&gt; branch (yes, I am aware the Cinnamon maintainer has a PPA for nightly builds, but I'm not quite that brave).  I installed it with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;sudo add-apt-repository ppa:lestcape/cinnamon
sudo apt-get install cinnamon
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Once installed you need to logout and choose Cinnamon from the login session screen, like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cinnamon" src="http://b038a8f209e36fc36fba-a9b634eed6b534d774260bd8467c190d.r61.cf1.rackcdn.com/Cinnamon-login.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that you will see a much more responsive UI.  And for you Windows users, it will feel very familiar, as the taskbar and icons are in the usual locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="desktop" src="http://b038a8f209e36fc36fba-a9b634eed6b534d774260bd8467c190d.r61.cf1.rackcdn.com/screenshot.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: To those that actually read this, I did try &lt;a href="http://packages.ubuntu.com/trusty/gnome-session-fallback"&gt;gnome session fallback&lt;/a&gt; and had many issues with it.  I am also aware that there is an official &lt;a href="http://ubuntugnome.org/"&gt;Ubuntu Gnome&lt;/a&gt; variant of Ubuntu now also.  Hadn't tried it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/not-a-fan-of-ubuntu-unity-trying-out-cinnamon-desktop-environment/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 04:11:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting a Canon MX450 Series Working With Ubuntu 14.04</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/getting-a-canon-mx450-series-working-with-ubuntu-1404/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I needed to scan something on my Canon MX450 series printer from my laptop running Ubuntu 14.04 LTS.  I had already setup the printer portion successfully with the built in network printer detection, but hadn't done the scanning portion.  I found out I needed to download a deb file and install something called scangearmp to get this to work.  The download button can be found &lt;a href="http://support-sg.canon-asia.com/contents/SG/EN/0100517701.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  As of this post I've download version 2.10 which was last updated on 14-Feb-2013, Issue Number 0100517701.  Once downloaded issue the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;tar xzf scangearmp-mx450series-2.10-1-deb.tar.gz
cd scangearmp-mx450series-2.10-1-deb/
sudo ./install.sh
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This will install the scangearmp binary to /usr/bin/scangearmp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now all you need to do is run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;scangearmp
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you you don't see a scanner listed in the dropdown then you just need to push the "Update Scanner List" button and it should find your scanner.  After that you should see the same popup but now with your Canon MX450 scanner listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="SelectScanner" src="http://b038a8f209e36fc36fba-a9b634eed6b534d774260bd8467c190d.r61.cf1.rackcdn.com/selectscanner.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps someone else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><category>troubleshooting</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/getting-a-canon-mx450-series-working-with-ubuntu-1404/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 03:03:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Restarting Audio in Ubuntu After Issues</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/restarting-audio-in-ubuntu-after-issues/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following command restarted audio for me in Ubuntu after my microphone on my headphones stopped working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;pulseaudio -k &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo alsa force-reload
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Credit to: &lt;a href="http://askubuntu.com/a/230893"&gt;http://askubuntu.com/a/230893&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/restarting-audio-in-ubuntu-after-issues/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 17:12:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I Finally Have Linux As My Native OS</title><link>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/i-finally-have-linux-as-my-native-os/</link><dc:creator>Jason Meridth</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I finally replaced OSX on my Mac with Ubuntu 14.04 LTS.  Out of the box I've had no issues.  Wireless, VPN, Terminal, Dropbox, Google Drive, LastPass, etc all work.  I was spending more time in my &lt;a href="https://www.vagrantup.com/"&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; VMs with OSX anyway.  Loved &lt;a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/"&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; + Vagrant.  Never had an issue.  I just wasn't using any portion of OSX.  It is nice to troubleshoot any issues and tweak my setup.  I'm getting used to Unity and may drop it for Gnome3 and Gnome-Do.  We'll see.  Any new things I troubleshoot or find, I'll post on.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>linux</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>http://blog.jasonmeridth.com/posts/i-finally-have-linux-as-my-native-os/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 23:27:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>