<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cli on Learn, Converse, Share</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/tags/cli/</link><description>Recent content in Cli on Learn, Converse, Share</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 15:36:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jmeridth.com/tags/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Personal VIM Cheatsheet</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/personal-vim-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 15:36:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/personal-vim-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Originally posted on 03-03-2014 and continually updated
Will be adding to this post as I learn/remember shortcuts
. - repeat last command in normal mode @: then @@ - repeat last command entered with : source # - find all occurances of the word I&amp;rsquo;m currently on dfc - delete everything including the letter &amp;lsquo;c&amp;rsquo; dtc - delete everything up to the letter &amp;lsquo;c&amp;rsquo; :e! - reload current file (typically after doing a git pull) :b# - go back to previous buffer shift+h - go to top of screen shift+m - go to middle of screen shift+l - go to bottom of screen ctrl+v [h|j|k|l] - highlight individual items (great for highlighting column(s) gUiw - capitalize the current word gUU - capitalize current line vU - capitalize current character guiw - lowercase the current word guu - lowercase the current line vu - lowercase current character [num]j - go down num lines from current line [num]k - go up num lines from current line ctrl+O - jump back to previous (older) location in file info ctrl+I - jump forward to next (newer) location in file info ctrl+w + [H,J,K,L] - move current window to the far left, bottom, top or right keybindings I use all the time via mappgings in my .</description></item><item><title>Meta keys with iTerm and Weechat</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/meta-keys-with-iterm-and-weechat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 10:12:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/meta-keys-with-iterm-and-weechat/</guid><description>Found this tip today about how to ensure your iTerm console sends +Esc to weechat for the meta keys to work properly.
To make alt key bindings behave well for Mac OS X iTerm2, go to Preferences-&amp;gt;Profiles-&amp;gt;Keys and click +Esc radio button for option keys.
I like to use meta+c to clear a buffer and meta+x to close a buffer. meta for me is the Alt key. Here is the keybindings in my .</description></item><item><title>Weechat keyboard shortcuts</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/weechat-keyboard-shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 23:52:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/weechat-keyboard-shortcuts/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve switched from using irssi to Weechat since I rejoined the ranks as a Racker.
Here is my current weechat.conf file
Some of the ones I use often:
ctrl+h - window left ctrl+j - window down ctrl+k - window up ctrl+l - window right ctrl+z - window zoom (make current small window full screen) ctrl+n - next buffer ctrl+p - previous buffer ctrl+y - clipboard paste ctrl+r - search ctrl+j - stop search normal commands not included with my weechat.</description></item><item><title>How to Run a Single Test With Tox</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/how-to-run-a-single-test-with-tox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 04:49:53 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/how-to-run-a-single-test-with-tox/</guid><description>I have to run a single python test once in a while and keep forgetting how to do it with Tox.
Here it is:
tox -e py27 -- project_name_here/tests/folder_name1_here/folder_name2_here/test_file_name_here.py:TestClassName.test_method_name Hope this helps someone else.
Happy bit twiddling.</description></item></channel></rss>