<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Information on Learn, Converse, Share</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/tags/information/</link><description>Recent content in Information on Learn, Converse, Share</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 09:43:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jmeridth.com/tags/information/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I Blog</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/why-i-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 09:43:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/why-i-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked recently why I blog. My answer is the same since I started blogging back in 2006. I blog for three reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I figured out a problem/issue I was having and want to share the knowledge. If I had the problem/issue, someone else will and hopefully google will link to my post and help them when they are searching. What I&amp;rsquo;ve also experienced is someone reads my post and comments with a better and/or more efficient solution. I then can link to their comment/post or update my own. I love that sense of community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will use a different part of my brain to write the post and, therefore (hopefully), remember the solution better next time this particular problem/issue arises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to store the solution online, not only on my local computer (aka isolation), so that I, and others, can reference it in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; blog because I think it will make me popular or because I want to seem smarter than anyone else. I enjoy learning and sharing information.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Slicehost Articles</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/slicehost-articles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 04:49:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/slicehost-articles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you are Linux newbie or are still unsure about how to setup your &lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt; box/slice/server, take a serious look at the &lt;a href="http://articles.slicehost.com/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Slicehost Articles&lt;/a&gt;.  Other articles include setup of Apache, Nginx, Postfix, MySQL, Ruby on Rails, Capistrano, SSH, Self-signed certificates, Django, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the Only Windows guys who read this, these articles are a great way to get your feet wet with Linux.  Can&amp;rsquo;t hurt your pocket book.  It&amp;rsquo;s free. &lt;a href="http://www.ubuntu.com" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; is currently my favorite distribution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>