<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tmux on Learn, Converse, Share</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/tags/tmux/</link><description>Recent content in Tmux on Learn, Converse, Share</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 08:46:04 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jmeridth.com/tags/tmux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Copying Text With Mouse In TMUX</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/copying-text-with-mouse-in-tmux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 08:46:04 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/copying-text-with-mouse-in-tmux/</guid><description>TL;DR Hold down shift key and select text with left mouse button. This will copy to clipboard. Then hold down the shift key again and click the middle button on your mouse. Voila!
Long version: After finally moving over to Ubuntu as my native operating system, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the default Terminal application for development. I run my weechat IRC session on a remote node in TMUX so I can detach/reattach at will and stay connected.</description></item><item><title>TMUX Cheat Sheet</title><link>http://jmeridth.com/posts/tmux-cheat-sheet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://jmeridth.com/posts/tmux-cheat-sheet/</guid><description>Install TMUX
sudo apt-get install tmux personal config file is at ~/.tmux.conf
change prefix to ctrl-a instead of default ctrl-b (easier on my hands)
unbind C-b set -g prefix C-a Outside of session Link to heading tmux list-sessions List all sessions tmux list-keys List all key bindings tmux list-commands List all commands tmux source-file ~/.tmux.conf Reload TMUX conf file tmux a -t session_name Attach to named session Inside of session Link to heading Ctrl-a, new -s session_name Create new named session Ctrl-a, c Create new window Ctrl-a, , Rename window Ctrl-a, w List windows Ctrl-a, l Move to previously selected window Ctrl-a, n Move to next window Ctrl-a, p Move to previous window Ctrl-a, d Leave session Ctrl-a, s List sessions - default, if not mapped elsewhere Ctrl-a, ?</description></item></channel></rss>